buzzlogic.com 2011-11-01

# Privacy Policy | BuzzLogic

**Last updated May 24, 2010**

BuzzLogic, Inc (”BuzzLogic,” “we,” “us,” or “our”) takes the privacy and protection of personal information very seriously. We may collect information about you and use and disclose such information, as described in this privacy policy (”Privacy Policy”).

BuzzLogic’s information usage practices are based on two beliefs: first, that protecting user privacy is essential to the growth and prosperity of the Internet; second, that a personalized web experience can provide significant benefits to Internet end users if done properly. In accordance with these beliefs, BuzzLogic creates results for advertisers and publishers in revolutionary ways without compromising individual privacy.

**WHAT THIS PRIVACY POLICY COVERS** “PII” means information that is personally identifiable like names, addresses, e-mail addresses, or phone numbers, as well as other non-public information that is associated with the foregoing. We only collect PII if you initiate contact to us through the BuzzLogic, Inc. corporate website at www.buzzlogic.com (the “BuzzLogic Site”) or join our Individual Publisher program. “NPII” means non-personally identifiable information that is not associated with or linked to your PII. NPII does not, by itself, permit the identification of individuals. NPII includes information such as the Prospect’s IP address, date and time of visit, domain type, and activity on a Partner Site.

BuzzLogic works with companies that wish to have their ads displayed (”Advertisers”) and other companies and web properties that display ads and/or otherwise partner with us (”Partners”). Persons who visit the sites of our Partners (”Partner Sites”) are referred to as “Prospects.”

This Privacy Policy describes BuzzLogic’s use of NPII that we collect when you visit our Partner Sites. This Privacy Policy also describes

BuzzLogic’s use of PII and NPII that we collect when you visit the BuzzLogic Site. 

  * For terms applicable to visitors of Partner Sites, browse to [Section I] of this Policy.
  * For terms applicable to visitors and users of the BuzzLogic Site, visit [Section II.]
  * Be sure to visit [Section III] for terms generally applicable to all users and visitors of our Partner Sites and the BuzzLogic Site.

For visitors of the BuzzLogic Site: By visiting or using the BuzzLogic Site, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy and you expressly consent to the processing of your PII that you volunteer to us according to this Privacy Policy. We may process your PII in the country where it was collected as well as other countries (including the United States) where laws regarding processing of PII may be less stringent than the laws in your country.

**I. PARTNER SITES**

_Information We Collect_  
When a Prospect visits a Partner Site, we use technology including, without limitation, “cookies” and “pixel tags,” to collect and store that Prospect’s NPII.

Cookies are small text files that uniquely identify a web browser. They are sent to a computer by web site operators or third parties. Almost all websites utilize cookies to one extent or another, and most web browsers are initially set up to accept cookies. Prospects receive cookies when they visit Partner Sites.

Pixel tags (also known as web beacons or clear GIFs) are small strings of code used in connection with delivering graphic images, files, or objects on a web page. Pixel tags allow the operator of the web page, or a third party who serves the pixel tag, to set, read and modify cookies on, and to transfer other data to, the browser used to view the web page. Pixel tags may also be used to obtain information about the computer being used to view that web page. The sender of the tag can view the IP address of the computer that the tag is sent to, the time it was sent, the user’s operating system and browser type and other similar information.

We use pixel tags and cookies that Partners place on their Partner Sites (or that are served via online ads) to collect NPII from a Prospect. We also set pixel tags on Partner Sites through various methods, including, without limitation, by serving an ad on the Partner Site (”ad pixel”); by incorporating a tag directly on the Partner Site (”site pixel”); or by incorporating a widget on the Partner Site (”widget pixel”). We may use logs from our ad servers to decide what type of pixel tag to set upon a Prospect’s next visit to a Partner Site. When a Prospect visits a Partner Site, a BuzzLogic pixel tag may be used to set a cookie on the Prospect’s browser. This cookie allows the Prospect to be recognized when he or she visits another Partner Site. That Partner Site will then show an ad tailored to the Prospect’s characteristics and preferences based on NPII that BuzzLogic has collected from that Prospect’s previous visits to Partner Sites.

We may also: (a) obtain NPII from Partners, Advertisers, and other third-party sources and combine it with other NPII that we have already collected or will collect, and (b) work with Partners who set pixel tags and cookies on our Partner Sites and share NPII of Prospects with us.

Our Partner Sites may separately collect NPII or other information from Prospects. This Privacy Policy does not apply to the privacy practices of our Partner Sites, and we are not responsible for their collection of NPII or other information from Prospects.

_Opting Out_  
At any time you may opt out of BuzzLogic’s collection and use of NPII on our Partner Sites (as described further below) by going here Please note that this browser-based opt out tool only works with the browser in which it is installed, and will only function if that browser is set to accept third-party cookies). To prevent collection of your NPII by BuzzLogic, the browser will set an opt-out cookie. If that opt-out cookie is deleted, BuzzLogic will resume collecting NPII from that browser until an opt-out cookie is reset on that browser. Check your browser’s “Help” files to learn more about handling cookies.

Note that, even if you have opted out, we or our Partner Sites may deliver ads based on NPII that is not targeted at you, based on such factors as the type of browser, time of day, number of ads served to a particular site, or general statistical reporting on the overall activity on a site.

To learn more about how to opt-out of data collection and preference based advertising programs, please visit the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) website here.

_Use Of Information We Collect_  
BuzzLogic analyzes NPII of Prospects to determine their behavior, content consumption and usage patterns on the Partner Sites. We also analyze NPII from various sources and at different times to define certain Prospect groups based on behavior and demonstrated preferences, and to place Prospects within those groups. We use the results of such analysis to develop and improve the services we offer and to serve ads on Partner Sites that are relevant to Prospects. We give our Partners a limited right to use a Prospect’s affiliation with a group as a basis for targeting display advertisements and similar commercial content intended to best reflect the Prospect’s preferences. This is designed to help ensure ads shown to Prospects visiting Partner Sites are relevant and useful.

_Disclosure Of Information We Collect_  
BuzzLogic may share NPII collected through its Partner Sites (either alone or combined with other NPII that BuzzLogic obtains from other sources) with its Partners and Advertisers. We share such NPII for our Partners and Advertisers to use for the purposes of media planning, ad targeting, and analysis and reporting of activities and trends among web users. For example, an Advertiser may implement ad targeting by using shared NPII that is related to a specific cookie to display relevant ads based on the content viewed or search terms entered in connection with that cookie. We may indicate to our Advertisers and Partners a Prospect’s membership within a group at various times by methods such as tagging an anonymous Prospect as a member of a group when the Prospect views certain web pages that are operated or controlled by a Partner. Our Advertisers and Partners may use a Prospect’s membership within a group to display advertisements and other content targeted to the demonstrated preferences of the Prospect. Our Advertisers and Partners may also use third-party service providers to display advertising or other content that reflects a Prospect’s membership in a group. We do not authorize our Advertisers or Partners to resell or sublicense NPII they receive from us to third parties. Please note that our Advertisers and Partners have their own privacy policies and data retention policies, and that we are not responsible for their use of a Prospect’s NPII.

We may provide reports to our Advertisers and Partners who access NPII. These reports are prepared using aggregated reports on overall Prospect activity on Partner Sites. Our reports do not contain any PII. Our Advertisers or Partners may use these reports to determine information about available Prospect groups. These reports may also be used for billing, auditing and other operational purposes.

_Internet Advertising Bureau_  
BuzzLogic, Inc. is a member of the Internet Advertising Bureau (”IAB”). The IAB is made up of online marketing, analytics, advertising, publishing, and email companies that are committed to examining and developing responses to important privacy and consumer protection issues in emerging media. You can learn more about the IAB’s views on privacy, as well as practices and procedures, [here.](http://www.iab.net/)

**II. BUZZLOGIC SITE**

_Information We Collect_  
We only collect PII that you submit to us voluntarily by contacting us through the BuzzLogic Site: 

  * For Individual Publishers: We collect your name and address and other information that is necessary for the payment of any fees due and payable in connection with any such program (including, without limitation, necessary tax-related information, such as your tax identification number).
  * For BuzzLogic Site visitors: If you contact us to learn more about our business or services, we will collect your name, the company you are working for, your e-mail address, and your telephone number. We may also collect, on an optional basis, your title, the city, state/province, and country you are located in. If you contact us by sending us an e-mail, we will collect any information that is contained in (and/or attached to) your e-mail.

When you visit the BuzzLogic Site, we may also collect NPII through technological means. We may use log files to collect Internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform type, and date/time stamp.

_Use of Information We Collect_  
We use information (including PII) you submit through the BuzzLogic Site to us, or to third parties that support us in collecting information, to provide you and others with our services, to enable your participation in our programs, to respond to requests that you make, to improve our services and to better tailor the features, performance and support of our services. We may also use your PII to provide you with notifications related to your use of our services, such as electronic newsletters or promotional e-mails, should you request to receive such communications from us.

We may create NPII from PII by excluding information that makes the information personally identifiable to you. We may use NPII to analyze usage of the BuzzLogic Site to optimize the site and our services. We also reserve the right to use and disclose any NPII collected through or derived from the BuzzLogic Site at our discretion.

_Disclosure of Information We Collect_  
Except to the extent expressly set forth in Section III of this Privacy Policy, we do not trade, rent, or share the PII that we collect through the BuzzLogic Site with third parties, unless you ask or authorize us to do so.

_Feedback_  
If you provide feedback to us, we may use and disclose such feedback for any purpose, provided we do not associate such feedback with your PII. We will collect any information contained in such feedback and will treat the PII in it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

_Choices Regarding Personal Information_  
If you receive any newsletter or promotional communication from us, you may opt out of receiving further promotional communications by contacting us as described below. We may send you service-related announcements (such as, but not limited to, notice that we have changed our services or the Privacy Policy) when we believe it is necessary to do so. You may not opt-out of these communications, which are not promotional in nature. You may request deletion of your PII by us by contacting us as described below, but please note that we may be required (by law or otherwise) to keep this information and not delete it (or to keep this information for a certain time, in which case we will comply with your deletion request only after we have fulfilled such requirements). When we delete any information, it will be deleted from the active database, but may remain in our archives.

**III. GENERAL**

_Third-Party Service Providers_  
We may also share NPII collected through Partner Sites or the BuzzLogic Site, and PII that you volunteer to us through the BuzzLogic Site, with third-party service providers in order for those service providers to perform business functions for us or on our behalf, such as the administration of our Individual Publisher program or the analysis of NPII that we collect.

_Affiliates_  
We may share some or all of your PII or NPII with any parent company, subsidiaries, joint ventures, or other companies under common control (collectively, “Affiliates”), in which case we will require our Affiliates to honor this Privacy Policy.

_Acquisition of BuzzLogic_  
In the event BuzzLogic goes through a business transition such as a merger, acquisition by another company, or sale of all or a portion of its assets, your PII or NPII will likely be among the assets transferred. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of BuzzLogic or its assets may continue to use your PII and NPII as set forth in this Privacy Policy. You hereby consent to BuzzLogic sharing your PII under the above circumstances.

_Required Disclosures_  
We may (and you authorize us to) disclose information we have collected from and about you (including PII) if we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to (a) comply with relevant laws or to respond to subpoenas or warrants served on us; (b) to enforce any agreement we may have entered into with you and to enforce the Privacy Policy; or (c) to protect and defend the rights or property of us, the users of our services, or third parties. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection.

_Security & Data Retention_  
BuzzLogic employs industry-standard security measures designed to ensure the security of all data. Any data that is stored on BuzzLogic’s servers is treated as proprietary and confidential and is not available to the public. BuzzLogic has an internal security policy with respect to the confidentiality of data, allowing access only to those employees or third parties who have a need to know such information for the purpose of delivering BuzzLogic products and services by means of user login and password requirements. BuzzLogic routinely evaluates its data security practices to identify security threats or opportunities for improvement.

No data security measures or transmission of data over the Internet, however, are guaranteed to be completely secure. It may be possible for third parties not under the control of BuzzLogic to intercept or access transmissions or private communications unlawfully. While we strive to protect your information, BuzzLogic cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us. You acknowledge and assume this risk when communicating with us.

BuzzLogic generally retains any information collected through cookies for up to approximately six months. When we delete information, it is deleted from our active databases but may remain in our archives. BuzzLogic reserves the right to retain information to the extent required by law or regulation.

_Children’s Privacy And Spam_  
BuzzLogic’s web site, products, and services are not developed for or directed at children. Children (persons under the age of 18) are not eligible to do business with us, and we do not intentionally collect PII from any person under the age of 13. BuzzLogic is committed to proper Internet practices and full compliance with the CAN-SPAM Act of 2003 (15 U.S.C. § 7701). It is our policy to prohibit the sending of unsolicited or “Spam” e-mail by BuzzLogic or any of its marketing partners.

_Third-Party Websites_  
The BuzzLogic site contains links to other third-party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of those other websites. You should check the privacy policies of those other websites to understand their practices.

_Consent And Changes_  
BuzzLogic reserves the right to update this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make a material change to this Privacy Policy, we will post such change on this page, update the effective date and post a prominent notice on the BuzzLogic Site. Any material changes to this Privacy Policy will be effective upon thirty (30) calendar days following our posting of notice of the changes on the BuzzLogic Site. These changes will be effective immediately for new users of the BuzzLogic Site or new Prospects.

_Contact Us_  
For more information or if you have questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy, please email us at privacy@BuzzLogic.com or you can send correspondence to the following address:

BuzzLogic, Inc.,  
Privacy Officer,  
425 Brannan Street  
San Francisco , CA 94107

© Buzzlogic Inc. 2010, All Rights Reserved
